Joshua Kennedy

Professional Tinkerer Resides in Scotland





Experience

Cloud Automation Engineer

NatWest - Since September 2021

- > Joined a small R&D team with the purpose of expanding the banks onprem cloud computing capabilities. Honed skills in Openshift, Kubernetes and general container orchestration.
- > Worked closely with colleagues from other teams to deliver proof of concept pieces for certificate automation via cert-manager and centralised secret management via Hashicorp Vault

Middleware Systems Engineer

NatWest - February 2019 - September 2021

- > Built automation to streamline common support tasks for deployment orchestration tooling within a small feature team. One of the tasks automated was agent upgrading. This facilitated the upgrade of over 1600 agents in the span of 6 months across 50 different teams. A feat that would have otherwise been unachievable in a reasonable timeframe.
- > Provided support for users and administrators in deployment orchestration. Created a large amount of documentation and hosted workshops. This resulted in the upskilling of an entire support team in the administration of related tooling.

Middleware Technical Analyst

NatWest - January 2018 - February 2019

- > Delivered technical support for Java based enterprise software, providing successful resolution for over 150 individual incidents.
- > Developed infrastructure support scripts for and assisted in standing up deployment orchestration tooling. Aquired new skills in RESTful API interaction and high availability clustering technologies as a result.

WebSphere Technical Apprentice

NatWest - January 2016 - January 2018

- > Developed knowledge on KornShell scripting and used it to automate a manual licensing process for ~5000 servers.
- > Audited and improved a certificate renewal tracking workflow. Obtained skills in Visual Basic and SQL along the way.



Education and Certification

Red Hat Certified Specialist in Containers and Kubernetes July 2022

Proficiency in podman, kubernetes & OpenShift

IT & Telecoms Professional January 2017 - January 2018 SCQF Level 8, QA Apprenticeship

IT & Telecoms Professional January 2016 - January 2017 SCQF Level 6, QA Apprenticeship

Personal Projects

Snowdon II WiFi

C / Programmable IO

A hardware mod for the Snowdon II soundbar. Implements a HTTP server and infrared NEC encoder from scratch to enable IR remote code signalling over WiFi.

Stateful

C / Javascript

A Pebble watchapp designed to control RESTful API's with minimal clicks

MPRIS Panel

Javascript / DBus

A media controller for linux that uses a 'smart-switching' technique to effortlessly control multiple media sources.

Tvcom

Python

A python module that provides a friendly interface for commanding legacy LG tvs via a serial connection.

About me

I have built a career on exploring rabbit holes. As it turns out, rabbits come in many colours and I have yet to find one that did not have something to offer. I have had as much fun trying to perfect my latest cooking endeavour as I've had trying to digest the broad strokes of quantum mechanics. In applying this same exploratory enthusiasm to computing I have found my life's work. For over a decade I have been delving deeper and deeper into the field of computing. From games development to container orchestration to signal processing I have with each step been building holistic knowledge of the field. In recent years I have finally made it down to the metal, exploring concepts such as Embedded C, Programmable IO and FPGA design through my personal projects.

Skills

Embedded C Golang Linux **Container Orchestration Python** JavaScript Programmable IO

Contact

Verilog

kennedn@msn.com

🤝 kennedn.com

in kennedn

C kennedn